<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://dcc-ex.com</id>
  <title>DCC-EX News</title>
  <updated>2023-05-24T06:26:02.805435+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://dcc-ex.com"/>
  <link href="https://dcc-ex.com/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://ablog.readthedocs.io/" version="0.11.3">ABlog</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230515.html</id>
    <title>DCC-EX Releases 5A EX-MotorShield8874</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Antoine</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img alt="DCC-EX News" class="image-product-logo-float-right" src="https://dcc-ex.com/_images/product-logo-news.png" style="width: 320.0px; height: 64.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;section id="dcc-ex-releases-5a-ex-motorshield8874"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DCC-EX, a global contributor to DCC open source software for model railroading, is proud to announce the first of our open source hardware products: the EX-MotorShield8874 providing dual 5 amp DCC and DC PWM (pulse width modulation) output for DCC-EX Command Stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EX-MotorShield8874 addresses the needs of DCC-EX users wanting to run multiple locos, across multiple power districts without requiring expensive DCC boosters. A DCC-EX Command Station can now outperform commercial DCC command stations which typically have single 3-3.5A or 5A output capabilities, and doing so at a fraction of the cost and with more advanced features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EX-MotorShield8874 is the first offering in the DCC-EX open source hardware ecosystem specifically designed for model railroaders, and is a direct result of the strong community engagement DCC-EX strives to inspire. DCC-EX hardware lead Paul Antoine says “the open source vision for hardware designs from the DCC-EX community means individual users can order small batch manufacturing of all DCC-EX endorsed designs for themselves, friends and fellow club members. Or they have the choice to buy the same quality of product from licensed local resellers in their countries of origin.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="DCC-EX EX-MotorShield8874 RevA Semify" src="https://dcc-ex.com/_images/ex_motorshield8874.jpeg" style="width: 750.0px; height: 500.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Featuring dual 5A output Texas Instruments DRV8874 MOSFET H-Bridge ICs, the EX-MotorShield8874 shield is fully drop-in compatible with the industry standard Arduino Motor Shield R3 due to additional logic onboard, along with plenty of new features. As a result, it can immediately replace older L298 based boards without software modifications. There is no need to have to cut traces or bend out pins, and the EX-MotorShield8874 can power your EX-CommmandStation too! The DRV8874 H-Bridge ICs also include hardware overcurrent protection monitored by EX-CommandStation, in addition to the existing software-based overload protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DCC-EX specific features include single 2.1mm barrel jack DC power for both the DCC/DC output and to supply the underlying Command Station motherboard with inbuilt polarity protection. This eliminates the need for a separate power supply for the Command Station motherboard. An onboard switching power supply regulates the DCC track input voltage to a safe 7.2VDC to the motherboard via the VIN pin, ensuring its linear 5V and 3.3V regulators stay as cool as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EX-MotorShield8874 is also future-proof, being compatible with current Arduino UNO and Mega based DCC-EX command station motherboards, and the more powerful platforms under development which use 3.3V microcontrollers, such as STM32 Nucleo and ESP32 based designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EX-MotorShield8874 sports I2C support via an industry standard STEMMA QT/Qwiic connectors and pin headers making I2C bus connections easier than ever. The STEMMA QT/Qwiic ecosystem of I2C boards from Adafruit and Sparkfun are now the easiest I2C expansion boards to use. The DCC-EX team expects to add additional STEMMA QT/Qwiic based peripherals with model railroading friendly features in upcoming releases. An I2C SIP header is included to allow many I2C enabled OLED screens to plug directly into the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of the EX-MotorShield8874 was Inspired by a discussion on the Austrian 1zu160 N scale model railway forum between DCC-EX development team member Harald Barth and enthusiastic DCC-EX user Erwin Peterlin. Erwin then designed the prototype EX-MotorShield8874 in a matter of days. Erwin is a skilled Digital Design and Verification Engineer by day for his employer, Semify (semify-eda.com) of Austria, who kindly offered to fund the prototype boards. Semify has also arranged to sell their initial production test batch on Tindie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erwin worked closely with the DCC-EX team on specification of additional features to suit DCC-EX software, with early prototypes being provided to the DCC-EX team for testing and verification. We are proud to say that Erwin opted to become part of the DCC-EX team and will continue to work on future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erwin and Semify have graciously provided the design files for the EX-MotorShield8874 on an open source basis, allowing DCC-EX users to order small batches of up to 10 assembled units from manufacturers such as JLCPCB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs wanting to offer commercial quantities to their local communities should contact Semify (service &amp;#64; semify-eda.com) to arrange a bulk purchase, or DCC-EX (support &amp;#64; dcc-ex.com) when looking to use the design to manufacture. Licensing includes donating a royalty to DCC-EX per board sold. Semify has a separate arrangement with DCC-EX due to their funding of the prototyping and work on verifying and testing the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EX-MotorShield8874 is available immediately for purchase in the EU, USA and Canada via Semify’s Tindie store (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.tindie.com/products/semify/semify-dcc-ex-motor-shield/"&gt;https://www.tindie.com/products/semify/semify-dcc-ex-motor-shield/&lt;/a&gt;) starting at $US34.90 each, and in Australia, New Zealand and South East Asia from Millennium Engineering Pty Ltd (orders &amp;#64; milleng.com.au) for $AU55, plus shipping. It will also be available shortly in the UK through Chesterfield Model Making &amp;amp; Miniature Electronics (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://chesterfield-models.co.uk/product/semify-dcc-ex-motor-shield/"&gt;https://chesterfield-models.co.uk/product/semify-dcc-ex-motor-shield/&lt;/a&gt;), for £29.99 plus shipping. Expect further announcements re local availability in the US through DCC-EX directly and Smart Hobby LLC, with other countries to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design files and initial hardware documentation are at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/DCC-EX/EX-Hardware/tree/main/EX-Motorshield8874"&gt;https://github.com/DCC-EX/EX-Hardware/tree/main/EX-Motorshield8874&lt;/a&gt; and installation details at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dcc-ex.com/reference/hardware/motorboards/ex-motor-shield-8874.html"&gt;https://dcc-ex.com/reference/hardware/motorboards/ex-motor-shield-8874.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DCC-EX Website will have further documentation for the EX-MotorShield8874, and extended support in software will be included in the upcoming EX-CommandStation v5.0 release scheduled for late May 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230515.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>DCC-EX, a global contributor to DCC open source software for model railroading, is proud to announce the first of our open source hardware products: the EX-MotorShield8874 providing dual 5 amp DCC and DC PWM (pulse width modulation) output for DCC-EX Command Stations.</summary>
    <category term="ex-commandstation" label="ex-commandstation"/>
    <published>2023-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230409.html</id>
    <title>Final Version 4 Release (v4.1.5)</title>
    <updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Fred (FrightRisk)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img alt="DCC-EX News" class="image-product-logo-float-right" src="https://dcc-ex.com/_images/product-logo-news.png" style="width: 320.0px; height: 64.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;section id="final-version-4-release-v4-1-5"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the final version 4 release of &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;CommandStation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; before we move to version 5!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a minor bugfix release from the previous version 4.1.2. This release is a Bugfix release to fix the initialisation order to benefit Ethernet boards, to fix GitHub issue &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/DCC-EX/CommandStation-EX/issues/299"&gt;#299&lt;/a&gt; related to TurnoutDescription, and to fix command parsing for LCN (the Layout Control Nodes Accessory Network).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the latest version, see the &lt;a class="reference internal" href="download/ex-commandstation.html#latest-ex-commandstation-official-release"&gt;&lt;span class="std std-ref"&gt;Latest EX-CommandStation Official Release&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also an updated &lt;a class="reference internal" href="reference/downloads/documents.html#comprehensive-dcc-ex-jmri-decoderpro-getting-started-guide-pdf"&gt;&lt;span class="std std-ref"&gt;Comprehensive DCC-EX &amp;amp; JMRI DecoderPro Getting Started Guide PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; available for download to help you get up and running with &lt;a class="reference internal" href="reference/glossary.html"&gt;&lt;span class="doc"&gt;JMRI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; DecoderPro and &lt;span style="font-weight: 600; font-family: Audiowide,Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; color: #00353d; font-size: 110%; "&gt;DCC-&lt;span style="color: #00a3b9;"&gt;EX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look for some major new features soon in version 5.0!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230409.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>We’re excited to announce the final version 4 release of &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;CommandStation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; before we move to version 5!</summary>
    <category term="ex-commandstation" label="ex-commandstation"/>
    <category term="production" label="production"/>
    <category term="release" label="release"/>
    <published>2023-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230327.html</id>
    <title>Version 5 progress and a breaking change in the development branch</title>
    <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>peteGSX</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img alt="DCC-EX News" class="image-product-logo-float-right" src="https://dcc-ex.com/_images/product-logo-news.png" style="width: 320.0px; height: 64.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;section id="version-5-progress-and-a-breaking-change-in-the-development-branch"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are full steam ahead to a v5.0 release, making sure what’s in there is well tested to the limits of our resources, and has documentation available as we go. Amongst other things, this has resulted in one potentially “breaking” change for users of &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;RAIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;’s capability to run sequences/routes on startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking change:&lt;/strong&gt; The implicit AUTOSTART at the beginning of the “myAutomation.h” file for &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;RAIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; has been disabled, as we have found it confuses a great many first time users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, when your &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;CommandStation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; started up with a “myAutomation.h” file present, anything defined prior to the very first &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;DONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; statement would execute automatically. This was used to do things like set turnouts/points to a known startup position, automatically start routes or sequences for fully automated layouts, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of v4.2.31, this behaviour is disabled, meaning nothing defined in “myAutomation.h” will automatically start unless preceded by the &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;AUTOSTART&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; directive (see &lt;a class="reference internal" href="ex-rail/EX-RAIL-reference.html#ex-rail-functions"&gt;&lt;span class="std std-ref"&gt;EX-RAIL Functions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, we are currently at v4.2.37 of the &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;CommandStation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; development release, and these updates are continuing multiple times a week as we find/fix bugs and refine the software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some more highlights of what’s been done since the last news update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;New &amp;lt;JG&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;JI&amp;gt; commands for multi-track gauges such as current sensing (v4.2.20)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Static IP address now configurable for Ethernet shields (v4.2.24)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SAMD21 had a bug in EX-RAIL due to memory alignment, this likely improves 32-bit support for various microcontrollers (v4.2.25)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved stability/reliability of the &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;IOExpander&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; device driver (v4.2.26) and bug fix for analogue inputs (v4.2.34)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Updated the DFPlayer code to cope with a new variant of the popular sound board seen in the wild, and mods to the HCRS04 ultrasonic driver so it uses less CPU loop time (v4.2.28)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various LCD bug fixes (latest in v4.2.29)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code class="docutils literal notranslate"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;&amp;lt;z&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; direct I/O pin manipulation command (v4.2.35)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add new “FLAGS” device to the HAL to communicate Vpin changes outside of &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;RAIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to software such as &lt;a class="reference internal" href="reference/glossary.html"&gt;&lt;span class="doc"&gt;JMRI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (v4.2.37)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the above new features and fixes are currently undocumented which we will fix in the coming weeks. In the meantime, feel free to jump onto Discord and chat with the developers and keep up to date (&lt;a class="reference internal" href="support/contact-us.html"&gt;&lt;span class="doc"&gt;Contact Us&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230327.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>We are full steam ahead to a v5.0 release, making sure what’s in there is well tested to the limits of our resources, and has documentation available as we go. Amongst other things, this has resulted in one potentially “breaking” change for users of &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;RAIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;’s capability to run sequences/routes on startup.</summary>
    <category term="ex-commandstation" label="ex-commandstation"/>
    <category term="ex-ioexpander" label="ex-ioexpander"/>
    <category term="exrail" label="exrail"/>
    <published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230309.html</id>
    <title>Extra, extra, read all about it! Introducing DCC-EX News!</title>
    <updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>peteGSX</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img alt="DCC-EX News" class="image-product-logo-float-right" src="https://dcc-ex.com/_images/product-logo-news.png" style="width: 320.0px; height: 64.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;section id="extra-extra-read-all-about-it-introducing-dcc-ex-news"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, that’s right, the DCC-EX team are now publishing updates regularly with our new “DCC-EX News” feed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve come to realise we can do much better in communicating the various different projects the team is working on, when we are releasing new versions, when we’ve found/fixed bugs, and when we have news or announcements to share with all our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further adieu, we are sharing this very first post, and these will continue regularly as we have news to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s happening at the moment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re continuing to work towards our next major release which will be v5.0.0, and will include some great new features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Track Manager (formerly called DC Districts), allowing you to run more than two motor driver outputs in DCC, DC, or programming track modes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Support for newer generation, 32bit microcontrollers from STMicroelectronics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improvements to I&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;C connectivity including better timeout handling, the ability to reset the bus without rebooting the &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;CommandStation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and support for multiplexors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Included device drivers for &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;Turntable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;FastClock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;IOExpander&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re continuing to review and improve our website and ways to keep you informed (hence this news feed)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re working on new, open source hardware options to make the entry point to DCC-EX simpler for those who aren’t up to the level of DIY currently required&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to follow “DCC-EX News”, we will have the latest few posts published on the front page of our website, along with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dcc-ex.com/news.html"&gt;complete list here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use an RSS/Atom feed reader, you can add “DCC-EX News” by the URL “&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://dcc-ex.com/news/atom.xml"&gt;https://dcc-ex.com/news/atom.xml&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to sharing more news and information with you all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230309.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Yep, that’s right, the DCC-EX team are now publishing updates regularly with our new “DCC-EX News” feed!</summary>
    <category term="dcc-ex" label="dcc-ex"/>
    <category term="news" label="news"/>
    <published>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230309a.html</id>
    <title>EX-Toolbox released on the Play Store</title>
    <updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>flash62au (Peter)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;img alt="DCC-EX News" class="image-product-logo-float-right" src="https://dcc-ex.com/_images/product-logo-news.png" style="width: 320.0px; height: 64.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;section id="ex-toolbox-released-on-the-play-store"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;Toolbox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is a free, open source, Android app to help setup and configure your EX-CommandStation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;Toolbox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; can be installed on you phone or table via the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=dcc_ex.ex_toolbox"&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt; . (Or search in the Play Store for “EX-Toolbox”, including the quotes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;Toolbox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; you can perform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;CV Programming in the programming track (Service Mode)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;CV Programming in the main track (Operation Mode)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Servo motor testing and adjustment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sensor testing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Current Meter (Only available when connected to EX-CommandStation version 4.2.20 and above.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Track Manager (Only available when connected to EX-CommandStation version 4.2.7 and above.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://dcc-ex.com/news/posts/20230309a.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>&lt;span style="font-weight: bold; color: #00a3b9; font-size: 110%;"&gt;EX&lt;span style="color: #00353d;"&gt;&amp;#8209;Toolbox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is a free, open source, Android app to help setup and configure your EX-CommandStation.</summary>
    <category term="ex-toolbox" label="ex-toolbox"/>
    <published>2023-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
